ICICI Lombard will focus on this. It is
one of the leading private general insurance companies in the country and the company's results have
come. Let me quickly tell you how the results are
clearly looking good. Profit has increased by 80% to Rs
350 crore. Net premium has increased by 10% to
almost Rs 3500 crore. Let us try to understand
the triggers in the results and what is the outlook going forward.
Gopal Balachandran, Communications and Risk Officer, is
with us.
Welcome to the show. First of all,
sir, please define how this quarter was
for the overall company and will this
performance continue? Will you continue this momentum
throughout the year?
Thanks. Thanks Swati for the data. I think if
you look at our growth, you are
right. I think the rule is 30% growth in the
aggregate premium and the growth that has come has
touched across the board. And our
focus segments have been motor health or
commercial lines. Across the board, we are
not even bear on all three sequences. You kind of
delivery growth if  Talking about motor,
our growth has been almost
27%. In this market, the
industry's growth has also been
at a similar level. If we talk about motivation,
health insurance is another segment where
our growth has been 33%. In space, the
industry's growth has been 21%. So,
we have had a great performance there through the
contribution of both corporate health
insurance and retail health insurance.
Commercial lines
is the third segment where we have always been
focused. In that segment also, we have nebulously kind of largely
maintained our
market share and date delivery growth. So
overall, I think we are quite happy with the way this growth has come, but the only thing is that it always leaves you to remember that it looks very,
very positive. Okay, the
growth momentum is looking positive, so we can
expect it to go well for this year.
Sir, I was looking at the claim ratio. There is a
small increase here, it is a marginal
increase. If we look at it, it has come to 72.1%.
What?  The region and what kind
of trends are we seeing regarding claims going forward.
If
you look at the wave of Covid impact
during that period, so far today motor insurance is
consentually we saw that fewer vehicles were plying
on the road and that for today officially there was a
positive impact of the loss ratio if you look at
last year's quarter by quarter,
if you look at now, it is back to
normal as of today, the number of
vehicles applying on the road is pretty much
higher than what has been seen during
free fall with times this series
and that is probably same increase happening on the
motor loss ratios on the higher
side again, what has been seen in, you know,
you should watch out for the train to seat for the
next couple of quarters ahead of nine, we have seen same
descent of cases of health claim
intimation that have come in this quarter, wait
and see whether it is a direction
change in so far as health  Intimation Sir,
consult on visible date. If you look at our overall
performance, the combined ratios
that we monitor are a
combination of both loss ratios and
expense ratios put together. I
think it has been stable at about 100% and
4.1%. In the last quarter, the
debt number was much higher at
123.5%, largely contributed by Covid
losses of the health carriers.
Okay Sir, the company has shown an underwriting loss
this time of ₹193 crore versus ₹39
crore on a quarterly basis. If I
look at the reason, Sir, what is the underwriting loss?
In our business, whatever
revenue we write, we earn it
and this is a policy contract, but
its expense, which is the cost of
distribution, less it is a friend,
so
we have to take the full value of constant distribution first, where the
benefit of revenue will come over the period.
Of time
the future over the next quarters onwards
and when the earnings will start to
play out in terms of the growth date.
Okay sir, I would like to know what will be the
strategy of the company now with respect to
auto finance. We have seen in the company,
year on year basis, there has been a decline in the
market share for new vehicles, but you have gained
market share in commercial vehicles, not from wrong with the two
wheeler. You are seeing stabilization here, so
what will be the strategy for auto loans.
So Swati, our focus has been on
motor insurance, particularly you and the thoughts which have been directly conducted concern,
our directive has been the market. We have seen that in the
last couple of years, we have seen
late growth and levels of
competitive intensity
given by multiple factors. Supply side
constraints, if you talk about it, were
really supplied, it constituted that, what was
excepted in the last couple of years,
as I said,
in the last quarter, the number of vehicles on
Roads were less and there was a lot of playing in over which
also lead to let's see elevated levels
of competitive intensity in
2022 our growth on motor insurance has been slightly
lower than the industry growth
numbers but thoughts are not consciously called data c want to do
because our focus is more
on android riding rates and just
delivery growth if we look at today's date
the benefit of let's see lower claims
insurance is behind us as I said the
number of vehicles back to track so c c
more number of cleaners getting intimated and
on the supply side constraints if we
talk
also science you be kind of coming back
particularly in the second half of d year c
expect d growth momentum to be positive
so in data background nine when you look at let's see
insurance from any motor vehicle
c r kind of extremely excited and
thoughts same c r continue to stay
invested which like motor insurance which is
sold at dealer channel I think c r
Kind of investing on making a lot in making show debt
wicket increment contribution from
debt particular distribution agency
distribution will also be our focus
if we talk about total agents for the
company than whole not just motor total agent the
debt number is also increase from almost what thousand which was end of the
financial increase to 94000 so all in all I
think CR can accelerate
with the opportunity we are
also seeing a lot of opportunity in motor insurance
and there is excitement going forward
quickly sir last question I would like to know from you I am
looking at the investment portfolio mix
it consists of 32.3% corporate
bonds and 48.5% GST how much impact sir
you see rising interest rates will have on
end born deals
one of the biggest advantages in our general insurance company is that
we do not have market
retirement so in every quarter
CR is not required to do mark to
market here if it is on  If you invest your equity
portfolio and fixed income
through the null, then debt helps you take
long-term calls in a super-deployment
system. And your question is, in terms
of high interest rates, you think actually it's very
positive in the long run because it helps
you kind of generate incremental
interest approvals on
investment debt. If you deploy it temporarily, there will be
other options which are not
required to take it through your books. So, you can
stay invested long-term
and you can deploy funds at higher
rates of interest which will lead to a
diversified outcome for your policy
thoughts. You are kind of making dose
investment calls and again over the years,
not just for one out of two years, over the last two years, if we consider this, we have been
operating on an investment book and have now generated an
aggregate return on our investment book which
comprises of both returns from
equity and  Friction less or almost
closed about 9 to 10% kind of return
over a 19 to 20 years cycle, thoughts what kind of
position
you have market impact but c just not
impact d PNR but highly treated
actually for generation,
okay so this is a positive thing
for the company and this time you should anticipate good growth for a good year,
thank you very much Gopal Balendra for joining me
and telling me what kind of numbers are there
and what kind of important
transactions are we seeing in the future, they have weak
numbers and business out, so this is the
top management of ICICI Lombard's conversation with us